KOTOMI ANN NOGUCHI

Lawrenceville, GA 30044 • <u>kotomi.noguchi@gmail.com</u> • (404) 649-1920 <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Blog</u>

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack developer with a passion for making positive impact through technology. Experienced with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with RESTful API architecture. Possess background in business and experience working in the e-commerce and tech space with strong skills in identifying technical solutions and building client relations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Node, Express, HTML5, CSS, Postgres, SQL, Heroku, Git, Jira, MaterializeCSS, Bootstrap, Material UI

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Vacay Away, GitHub | Demo

Vacation planner designed for flexibility, with the ability to schedule activities to specific vacation days or to the undecided list

- Built a dynamic and seamless UI with horizontal scrolling components for itinerary days with React.js and Material UI
- Applied Redux and Redux-Thunk to provide accessibility to data in a single global store and allow dispatching for an application easy to test and that runs in different environments

Flappy Bernie, <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Demo</u>

Interactive spin-off game of Flappy Bird, where the objective is to get through the pipes without hitting them or the ground.

- Constructed engaging gameplay UI using Object Oriented Javascript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Improved user experience by leveraging AJAX calls for data interactions between the client and Rails API, fetching the top scores from the database asynchronously

Life is Brewtiful, GitHub | Demo

Brewery reviewing app for beer lovers all over the U.S. with search tools to effortlessly filter through breweries.

- Designed Rails application with features like the "Top 100" page and user profile pictures using the Active Storage gem to boost user engagement and build community
- Utilized Open Brewery DB's API to pull and store 8000+ brewery data in PostgreSQL database
- Expanded user login options by including authentication with FaceBook and Google accounts via OmniAuth

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Visiture, LLC Atlanta, GA

Technical Account Manager

May 2019 - September 2020

- Managed 2-4 development projects at a time, writing concise, actionable tasks using the Agile methodology for our web developers to meet project deadlines and maintain client budget
- Optimized client e-commerce processes through native and custom Magento software, resulting in increased website traffic by up to 40% and sales conversion by 12%

The Japan Exchange and Teaching Program

Kyoto City, Japan

Assistant Language Teacher

July 2016 - July 2018

- Collaborated with over 30 public educators within teams across five schools to develop and improve lesson plans
- Volunteered to lead high school student groups for overnight weekend English camps to increase their comfort levels in being immersed in an English-speaking environment before leaving for their homestay programs in Australia
- Hosted school-wide "English Shower" events for 450 students to enjoy learning English through songs and activities

ExpandLab, LLC Atlanta, GA

Data Configuration Analyst Intern

October 2015 -July 2016

- Migrated clients' e-commerce sites to the Magento platform, performing online store, catalog, shipping, payment, cache, and SEO configurations to increase online sales and reach
- Screened quality control prior to project releases to ensure optimal user experience on client websites

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Atlanta, GA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Program

April 2021

Emory University, Goizueta Business School

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Business Administration, Concentration: Strategic Management Consulting Cumulative GPA: **3.70/4.0**, Dean's List Fall 2012 and Fall 2013

May 2016